Guide to the Clarke and Rapuano Records, 1940-1993
Clarke and Rapuano Records, 1940-1993
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Clarke and Rapuano records, 1940-1993
3047
Clarke & Rapuano
94.1 cubic ft.
Reports, plans, blueprints, photographs, publications, contracts, and drawings.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Reports and studies, including plans, blueprints, photographs, publications, contracts, and drawings pertaining to transportation, parkways, and city planning projects in Queens, Westchester County, Long Island, Buffalo, and New York, New York; Bethlehem, Pennsylvania; and other places. Also, includes planning material pertaining to the 1964 World's Fair in New York City and a report prepared for Cornell University on Cornell Heights, 1987.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Gilmore D. Clarke (Cornell University Class of 1913), 1892-1982, was Professor of Architecture at Cornell, 1935-1950, and Dean of the College of Architecture, 1939-1950. Michael Rapuano, 1904-1975, received an M.L.A. from Cornell in 1927.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Reports and studies, including plans, blueprints, photographs, publications, contracts, and drawings pertaining to transportation, parkways, and city planning projects in Queens, Westchester County, Long Island, Buffalo, and New York, New York; Bethlehem, Pennsylvania; and other places. Also, includes planning material pertaining to the 1964 World's Fair in New York City and a report prepared for Cornell University on Cornell Heights, 1987.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Clarke & Rapuano.; Clarke, Gilmore D., 1892-; Rapuano, Michael.; New York World's Fair (1964-1965); Cornell University--Planning.
Subjects:
City planning.; Highway planning.; Landscape architecture.; Transportation.; Parkways--New York (State); Parkways--Pennsylvania.; City planning--Pennsylvania--Bethlehem.; City planning--New York (N.Y.)--Flushing.; City planning--New York (N.Y.); City planning--New York (N.Y.)--Queens.; Landscape architects.; Planners.
Places:
Bethlehem (Pa.); Flushing (New York, N.Y.); New York (N.Y.); Queens (New York, N.Y.); Cornell Heights (N.Y.)--Description and travel.
Form and Genre Terms:
Blueprints.; Photographs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Records
  - Original accession of 1984 (Box 1-2)
  - Lee Avenue (#1 - original box number) (Box 3)
  - Flatland Avenue (#22) (also, 2 folders of Contract) (Box 4)
  - Contract Files (#14) Non-current P-Z (Box 5)
  - Contracts (Box 6)
  - Rushmore (also, 2 folders of contracts) "C" (Box 7)
  - Rushmore (Box 8)
  - LaSalle Arterial (also, 4 folders Rushmore) (Box 9)
  - Connecticut (Box 10)
  - Hutchinson River Parkway (#1) (Box 11)
  - PDIs Paulding Avenue Milford Street (Box 12)
  - Hutchinson River Parkway (Box 13)
  - Contract Files, Non-current M-P (Box 14)
  - Miscellaneous projects (Box 15-16)
  - Structures (Box 17)
  - LaSalle (Box 18)
  - Johnson Property, Chester, LaSalle (Box 19)
  - Bucks County, LaSalle (Box 20)
  - Saucon Valley Country Club, 1958-1960 (Box 21)
    Parking area bridge. Designs and estimates.
  - Unisphere, 1960-1963 (Box 21)
    For the 1964 World's Fair in Queens, New York. File includes correspondence; sketches; engineering computations; plans from American Bridge (US Steel was building the structure); photos of the 1939 Perisphere foundations
  - Jones Beach Parkway Authority: Ocean Parkway, 1965 (Box 21)
    Design and estimate.
    Shelter, pump pits, bus shelter, and lighting
  - Water Tower - Robert Moses State Park, Fire Island New York, 1965-1967 (Box 21)
    Preliminary and final designs and estimates
  - Hill to Hill Bridge and Approaches, 1970 (Box 21)
    Reports to the Commonwealth of Pennsylvania (with plans,) originals and mock up for bridge report, structural analysis
  - Lehigh University -RH-11, 1972 (Box 21)
    Borings and preliminary plans showing wall 1 and 2. Water study.
  - Lehigh University -RH-11, 1972-1974 (Box 21)
    Specifications/drawings and estimates
  - Structures Miscellaneous (Box 22)
  - LaSalle Arterial (Box 23)
  - Hutchinson River Parkway (Box 24-25)
  - Silver Sands (Box 26)
  - Middletown PC (Box 27)
  - Middletown FHWA Pres. & WBD (Box 28)
  - Pres. & WBD (Box 29)
  - Bethlehem - Hill to Hill Bridge, c. 1970 (Box 156)
    Includes plans
  - Bethlehem Interstate Spur Connection, 1958 (Box 156)
  - Hutchinson River Parkway: Section A - 2/2, 1984, 1994 (Box 156)
  - Photographs
    - Album and loose photos
      - Nashville, Tenn. (Box 30)
      - Rock Creek Park, D.C. (Box 30)
      - West Side Highway, N.Y.C. (Box 30)
      - Bethlehem, PA (Box 30)
      - Cleveland, OH (Box 30)
      - Middletown, Conn. (Wesleyan Univ. dormitories) (Box 30)
      - Palisades Parkway, NJ (Box 30)
      - Park Cliester Houses, Stuyvesant Town, NY (Box 30)
      - Pittsburgh, PA (Box 30)
      - Pedestrian Bridge, Queens Zoo, NY (Box 30)
    - Album of bridge designs
      - St. Regis Paper Co. (Box 30)
      - West Nyock, NY (Box 30)
      - Corning, NY (Box 30)
      - others (Box 30)
    - Album of designs and planning for:
      - SUNY Albany (Box 30)
      - Cleveland, OH (Box 30)
      - Bethlehem, PA (Box 30)
      - Scranton, PA (Box 30)
  - Projects Miscellaneous (Box 31)
  - Miscellaneous drawings, printed material (Box 32)
  - Miscellaneous Project files
    - Air Products Chemicals (Box 33-37)
    - Calverton National Cemetery (Box 33-37)
  - Silver Sands through Staten Island Botanical Garden; also USPS through West Basin Drive (Box 38-39)
  - Original Reports A-E (Box 40)
  - Original Reports H-H (Box 41)
  - Stirling Forest through Stony Brook (Box 42)
  - Stirling Forest; Calverton Reports (Box 43)
  - Original Reports H-O (Box 44)
  - Products: A through Insecticide; project drawings (Box 45)
  - Calverton; project files and drawings (Box 46)
  - Project Drawings (Box 47)
  - Original Specs: M (Box 48)
  - Project Drawings (Box 49)
  - Project Files: Irrigation systems (Box 50)
  - Original Specs: N through P
    - Nashville UC-4 796.33 three (Box 51)
    - New York City Dept. of Parks (Box 51)
    - Parsonage Farm, jPA material (Box 51)
  - Briley (Box 52)
  - Project Drawings: Calverton (Box 53)
  - Project Drawings (Box 54)
  - Project Drawings; bound reports A-B (Box 55)
  - Original Specs: A-C (Box 56)
  - Bound Reports: B-H (Box 57)
  - Original Specs: C (Box 58)
  - Bound Reports: I (Box 59)
  - Original Specs: C-F (Box 60)
  - Bound Reports: P-Z; Ford Motor Company
    - N.Y.C. Dept. of Parks, con't. (Box 61)
    - Norwalk, Darien Conn. (Box 61)
    - Kingdom of Saudi Arabia (Box 61)
    - Staten Island Museum, High Rock Park (Box 61)
    - Sun Inn, Bethlehem, PA (Box 61)
    - Tocks Island Region, NJ (Box 61)
    - Union Carbide (Box 61)
    - Sevises for Coast Guard Shore Facility, NJ, NY, N. England (Box 61)
    - Palisades Interstate Park Comm.; Sewage (Box 61)
    - Disposal Facilities, 1971 (Box 61)
    - Ford Motor Co. (Box 61)
  - Original Specs: G-J (Box 62)
  - Ford; other projects (Box 63)
  - Original Specs: J-L (Box 64)
  - Projects; Original Specs P-R
    - Great Neck, L.I. Railroad (Box 65)
    - Prudential Ins. Co. (Box 65)
    - Monmouth State Park (Box 65)
    - Kresge Bldgs, Bethlehem, PA, Urban Renewal (incl. photos, 1977 ) (Box 65)
    - Port Richmond (Box 65)
    - Purchase Park (Box 65)
    - River Park, Norwalk, Conn. (Box 65)
    - Rockland Cable Systems (Box 65)
  - Original Specs: P
    - NYC Dept. of Parks and Recreation, 1980s, incl. Wellowbrook (Box 66)
    - Perkins, Elmer (Box 66)
    - Pocono Mt. Joint Schools (Box 66)
    - Port Authority, NYC (Box 66)
    - Port Richmond, NYC (Box 66)
  - Original Specs: J-L; various projects (Cornell, Palisades Parkway, etc.) (Box 67)
  - Original Specs: R; Calverton; various projects (Box 68)
  - Various Projects; Cornell; Calverton (Box 69)
  - Various Projects (Box 70)
  - Various Projects; Original Specs: S (Box 71)
  - Original Specs: S (Box 72)
  - Original Specs: S; Merck; various projects (Box 73)
  - Various Projects (Box 74-75)
  - Merck (Box 76)
  - Various Projects (Box 77-80)
  - Air Products; Calverton (Box 81)
  - Calverton (Box 82)
  - Calverton; Central Park; Copley Square (Box 83)
  - Cornell (Central Avenue); D.C. Transportation; Flushing High School; Fordham; Glen Island Park; Morris; Neelytown; NYS Thruway; Northern State Parkway (Box 84)
  - Printed Specs Calverton; Fort Wadsworth; Gracie Mansion; Hutchinson Parkway (Box 85)
  - Printed Specs Hutchinson River; IBM; Iona Island; Kean College; Lehigh University; Linden Place; Newark State College; Lee Avenue (Box 86)
  - VA Cemetery, Washington; Calverton; Copley Square (Box 87)
  - Copley Square; Alfred Smith High School (Box 88)
  - Calverton; Merck;Mamaroneck; Mokattam; Neptune Ave; NJ College of Medicine (Box 89)
  - Calverton; NJ College of Dentistry; River Park; Short Hills; Prudential (Box 90)
  - Original Specs T-W (Box 91)
  - Northern State Parkway; Palisades Parkway; Park Ave; Parker Residence; Pentaquit; President's Park; Prudential, Short Hills (Box 92)
  - Prudential, Short Hills; Queensboro Bridge; RDSA (Box 93)
  - RDSA; Roosevelt Memorial; Route 139; Rushmore Associates (Box 94)
  - Rushmore Associates; Merck (Box 95)
- Plans
  - Purchase Park-Harrison, New York (Box 96)
  - Purchase Park-Harrison, New York (Box 97)
  - Copley Square-Boston, Massachusetts (Box 98)
  - Macombs Dam (Box 99)
  - Rockaway Freeway-Almeda Avenue (Box 100)
  - Hitachi (Box 101)
  - Hutchinson River Parkway (Box 102)
  - Flushing High School (Box 103)
  - Flushing High School (Box 104)
  - Rushmore-Orange County (Box 104)
  - Calverton National Cemetery (Box 105)
  - Calverton National Cemetery (Box 106)
  - Calverton National Cemetery (Box 107)
  - Calverton National Cemetery (Box 108)
  - Arneytown Veteran's Cemetery (Box 109)
  - Arneytown Veteran's Cemetery (Box 110)
  - Fort Wadsworth Naval Station (Box 111)
  - Fort Wadsworth Naval Station (Box 112)
  - Fort Wadsworth Naval Station (Box 113)
  - Fort Wadsworth Naval Station (Box 114)
  - Battleship Surface Action Group (Box 114)
  - Fieldbrook-Putnam County (Box 115)
  - Fieldbrook-Putnam County (Box 116)
  - Nassau and Bruckner Expressway (Box 117)
  - Nassau and Bruckner Expressway (Box 118)
  - Tidal Basin-Ohio Drive (Box 119)
  - Tidal Basin-Ohio Drive (Box 120)
  - Tidal Basin-Ohio Drive (Box 121)
  - Tidal Basin-Ohio Drive (Box 122)
  - Tidal Basin-Ohio Drive (Box 123)
  - Tidal Basin-Ohio Drive (Box 124)
  - Track and Playfields-Vanderbilt University (Box 124)
  - Tidal Basin-West Potomac Parks Road (Box 125)
  - Berry Houses (Box 125)
  - Harriman Toll Plaza (Box 126)
  - Port Richmond Avenue (Box 127)
  - Port Richmond Avenue (Box 128)
  - Martin Tower-Bethlehem Steel (Box 129)
  - Martin Tower-Bethlehem Steel (Box 130)
  - New Jersey College of Medicine and Dentistry (Box 131)
  - New Jersey College of Medicine and Dentistry (Box 132)
  - New Jersey College of Medicine and Dentistry (Box 133)
  - Lee Avenue, New York City (Box 134)
  - Lee Avenue, New York City (Box 135)
  - Citicorp (Box 136)
  - Residence of J. Seward Johnson (Box 137)
  - Residence of J. Seward Johnson (Box 138)
  - Residence of J. Seward Johnson (Box 139)
  - Residence of J. Seward Johnson (Box 140)
  - Van De Bovenkamp sculptures (Box 140)
  - President's Park (Box 141)
  - President's Park (Box 142)
  - Corona Park (Box 143)
  - Gracie Mansion (Box 144)
  - New York School for the Deaf (Box 145)
  - Alfred E. Smith High School (Box 146)
  - Langone Residence (Box 147)
  - Immaculate Conception Housing (Box 148)
  - Bronx Court House (Box 149)
  - Breeze Hill-Central Park (Box 150)
  - Syosset River Park (Box 151)
  - Central Park Mall-Reconstruction of Concert Ground (Box 152)
  - Coney Island (Box 153)
  - Broad Street Mall-Bethlehem, Pennsylvania (Box 154)
  - Joyce Kilmer Park (Box 154)
  - South Street Sea Port Deck Work (Box 154)
  - Parking Studies (Box 154)
  - Hunter Tier Parking (Box 155)
  - Stratford Marina (Box 155)
  - Pennsylvania Bridges (Box 155)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 155)
  - Hudson Hills (Box 157)
  - Atlantic Creosoting-Savannah, Georgia (Box 157)
  - Clove Park (Box 158)
  - Rockville, Maryland (Box 159)
  - Coney Island (Box 160)
  - Alley Pond (Box 161)
  - Olmsted Center (Box 161)
  - Tudor City Place (Box 162)
  - Silver Lake Park- Burkes County Pennsylvania (Box 162)
  - James Madison Memorial Library- (Library of Congress) (Box 163)
  - Robert Moses State Park (Box 164)
  - Flushing Avenue (Box 165)
  - Cornell Campus (Box 166)
  - Cornell Campus (Box 167)
  - Cornell Campus (Box 168)
  - Beebe Lake- Cornell University (Box 169)
  - United Nations Plaza Court (Box 170)
  - Palisades Interstate Parkway (Box 170)
  - Middletown Psychiatric (Box 170)
  - Putnam Fields (Box 171)
  - Naples Playground on Staten Island (Box 171)
  - Fordham University (Box 172)
  - Mary Harriman Rumsey Playground (Box 172)
  - North General Hospital (Box 172)
  - Bronx Zoo (Box 173)
  - New York Botanical Gardens (Box 173)
  - Lehigh Canal Park- Bethlehem, Pennsylvania (Box 174)
  - Central Park (Box 174)
  - Sterling Forest (Box 174)
  - Central Business District of Bethlehem, Pennsylvania (Box 174)
  - Monocacy Creek Urban Renewal (Box 174)
  - Seaport Plaza (Box 175)
  - New Jersey Educational Testing (Box 175)
  - Neelytown Center (Box 176)
  - Willowbrook Tennis (Box 176)
  - Fordham University (Box 177)
  - Port Authority (Box 177)
  - High Rise- Saudi Arabia (Box 178)
  - Eastchester and Tucahoe (Box 178)
  - Eagle Chase (Box 178)
  - Belmont Race Tarck (Box 178)
  - Short Hills Office Center- Essex County, New Jersey (Box 179)
  - Short Hills Office Center- Essex County, New Jersey (Box 180)
  - Staten Island Botanical Gardens (Box 181)
  - Morris Gardens (Box 181)
  - Snug Harbor (Box 181)
  - Rockefeller Gardens (Box 181)
  - Pepsi-Cola (Box 182)
  - IBM Office Building- Somers, New York (Box 182)
  - Miscellaneous Project #8708 (Box 183)
  - Miscellaneous Project #8708 (Box 184)
  - Beebe Lake- Cornell University (Box 185)
  - Westchester Avenue (Box 185)
  - Middletown Psychiatric Center (Box 185)
  - Miscellaneous Bridges (Box 185)
  - Erie Basin Port Authority (Box 185)
  - Montgomery County design location study (Box 185)
  - Hutchinson River Parkway (Box 185)
  - Lee Avenue (Box 185)
  - Fort Wadsworth Naval Station (Box 186)
  - Bronx River Parkway (Box 186)
  - Hitachi (Box 186)
  - Flushing High School (Box 186)
  - Construction Plans (Bound)
  - Sprain Parkway (Box 187)
  - Sprain and Hutchinson Parkway/West Point (Box 188)
  - Southern Tier Expressway (Box 188)
  - New York State Thruway - Berkshire Section (Box 188)
  - Westside Highway, c. 1974 (Box 189)
    Report
  - The New York Municipal Airport at Idlewild, 1946 (Box 189)
    Report of Design Committee
  - Pennsylvania Signage (Box 189)
  - Niagara Parkway (Box 189)
  - Niagara Expressway (Box 190)
  - Niagara Parkway, 1962 (Box 191)
  - Interstate Spur Connection - Bethlehem, Pennsylvania, 1958 (Box 191)
  - Pedestrian Mall - Bethlehem, Pennsylvania, 1976 (Box 191)
  - Highway 1010 - Delaware County, PA, 1970 (Box 191)
  - Infrastructure for the Mokattam, Egypt, 1980 (Box 191)
  - Silver Lake Park - Bucks County, PA, 1973 (Box 191)
  - Boylston Street Improvements Study - Boston, MA, 1986 (Box 192)
  - Cumberland Gap National Historic Park, 1973 (Box 192)
  - Palisades Interstate Park Commission, 1972 (Box 192)
  - Scajaquada Creek Expressway, 1959 (Box 192)
  - Mile Strip Road, 1965 (Box 192)
  - Baltimore/Washington Parkway, Young Street Arterial Highway, 1967-1968 (Box 193)
  - Tonawanda, NY (Box 193)
  - Sheridan Expressway, c. 1960 (Box 193)
  - IBM-Somers, New York (Map-case Item 1-2)
    Bound plans
  - L.R. 1000 Section G, Bucks County, PA, 1962 (Map-case Item 3)
    Bound location Study and Report
  - Niagara Parkway, 1960-1963 (Map-case Item 4-6)
  - Oversized Plans (Flat)
  - Presentation Boards: Bethlehem Urban Renewal, Gracie Mansion, Montgomery County, State Line Lookout Park (Map-case Folder 1)
  - Mammoth Battlefield State Park; Miscellaneous Oversize Photos (Map-case Folder 2)
  - New York World's Fair: Unisphere plans, 1960-1966 (Map-case Folder 3)
    Photostats: includes plans, sketches and for post-fair development (Previously Box 156)
  - New York World's Fair: Unisphere plans, 1960 (Map-case Folder 4)
    Armillary Sphere. Blueprints and Linens
  - New York World's Fair: Unisphere plans, 1961 (Map-case Folder 5)
    Preliminary Drawings. Pencil and blueprints
  - New York World's Fair, 1961 (Map-case Folder 6)
    Drawing of benches for the fair, layout of the fairgrounds, and for the Unisphere Foundation
  - New York World's Fair: Unisphere, 1962 (Map-case Folder 7)
    Official construction drawings for the Unisphere Foundation
    Signed by Robert Moses, William C. Potter, Stuart Constable, William Whipple Jr. and Gilmore D. Clarke